chinainternetwatch.com 2018-10-04

# CIW Privacy Policy – China Internet Watch

**Privacy Policy for chinainternetwatch.com**

 _Last updated on 22 May 2018_

The privacy of our visitors to chinainternetwatch.com (“CIW”) is important to us.

At chinainternetwatch.com, we recognize that privacy of your personal information is important. Here is information on what types of personal information we receive and collect when you use and visit chinainternetwatch.com, and how we safeguard your information. We never sell your personal information to third parties.

This privacy policy applies to the information obtained by us through your use of the Site, the Services, the Software (together, “Products”) and other China Internet Watch products and services.

If you choose to use PayPal® to finalize and pay for your order, you will provide your credit card number, directly to PayPal®. The privacy policy of PayPal® will apply to the information you provide on the PayPal® website. We also use [Stripe](https://stripe.com/) as our primary payment gateway to accept credit card payments; the privacy policy of Stripe will apply. We do no in any circumstances collect or store your credit card information.

### The type of personal information we collect

  * We collect certain personal information about visitors and subscribers of our digital content
  * The most common types of information we collect include things like: usernames, member names, email addresses, IP addresses, other contact details (such as email addresses), survey responses, photos, support queries, comments, content you direct us to make available on our websites and web analytics data.
  * For paying users, we collect payment information such as payment agent details, transactional details, tax information
  * We will also collect personal information from job applications

### How we use personal information

We collect this information in order to help us deliver and support our Products, including by localizing your experience. This information also helps us improve our understanding of how our users use the Products.

### Log Files

As with most other websites, we collect and use the data contained in log files. The information in the log files include your IP (internet protocol) address, your ISP (internet service provider, such as SingTel or AOL), the browser you used to visit our site (such as Chrome, Internet Explorer or Firefox), the time you visited our site and which pages you visited throughout our site.

### Cookies, Web Beacons, Third-Party Analytics Providers (TPAP)

We do use cookies to store information, such as your personal preferences when you visit our site. This could include only showing you a popup once in your visit, or the ability to login to some of our features, such as forums.

We also use third party advertisements on chinainternetwatch.com to support our site. Some of these advertisers may use technology such as cookies and web beacons when they advertise on our site, which will also send these advertisers (such as Google through the Google AdSense program) information including your IP address, your ISP, the browser you used to visit our site, and in some cases, whether you have Flash installed. This is generally used for geotargeting purposes (showing New York real estate ads to someone in New York, for example) or showing certain ads based on specific sites visited (such as showing cooking ads to someone who frequents cooking sites).

We allow TPAPs to track Visitors’ browsing history on the Site using first-party cookies (such as the Google Analytics cookie) and third-party cookies (such as the DoubleClick cookie). TPAPs may use the information stored by the cookies to, among other things, evaluate your use of a website, prepare reports of website activities for website operators and provide other services associated with website and Internet usage. The information tracked and stored by the cookies enables TPAPs to optimize and serve ads to the Site’s visitors on third-party websites. By using the Site, you agree to the forwarding of data to TPAPs and the processing by such TPAPs of the data collected from you in the manner and for the purposes described above.

To opt out of  _Google Analytics for Display Advertisers_  and customized Google Display Network ads, visit the [Ads Preferences Manager](https://www.google.com/settings/ads/onweb/?sig=ACi0TCiRDcnrXrdffABE6Nifr9QppTwHkj_NTB8gd0FaMd9YV_wg5YIp3OvYIp-y-pdTWNhIhLjQXh6TyIek2jcL233J8XokduMKuR1N-zHOJP2Ls6zIAM_wKkwTu-xTmML-Aucg-KSrCOB6oLAL11n-sPX9rEefGBMsmC7iVBTJsDKZmWkr3jnzCeVGR-wzwiV8cGO96yfR&hl=en). Profile information provided to CIW by you is, however, subject to disclosure pursuant to any applicable laws.

### Email Messages

We send our users email messages for new content and Products updates. We consider your acceptance of this Policy as your acceptance of our offer to send you these emails. You may opt-out of such communications at any time by clicking the “unsubscribe” link found within CIW email updates and changing your contact preferences. You will continue to receive essential account-related information, even if you unsubscribe from promotional emails.

### DoubleClick DART cookies

We also may use DART cookies for ad serving through Google’s DoubleClick, which places a cookie on your computer when you are browsing the web and visit a site using DoubleClick advertising (including some Google AdSense advertisements). This cookie is used to serve ads specific to you and your interests (”interest based targeting”). The ads served will be targeted based on your previous browsing history (For example, if you have been viewing sites about visiting Las Vegas, you may see Las Vegas hotel advertisements when viewing a non-related site, such as on a site about hockey). DART uses “non personally identifiable information”. It does NOT track personal information about you, such as your name, email address, physical address, telephone number, social security numbers, bank account numbers or credit card numbers. You can opt-out of this ad serving on all sites using this advertising by visiting http://www.doubleclick.com/privacy/dartadserving.aspx

You can choose to disable or selectively turn off our cookies or third-party cookies in your browser settings, or by managing preferences in programs such as Norton Internet Security. However, this can affect how you are able to interact with our site as well as other websites. This could include the inability to login to services or programs, such as logging into forums or accounts.

Deleting cookies does not mean you are permanently opted out of any advertising program. Unless you have settings that disallow cookies, the next time you visit a site running the advertisements, a new cookie will be added.

## Data storage, transfer, retention, and deletion

### Where is my Information stored?

Information submitted to Grammarly will be transferred to, processed, and stored in the United States. When you use the Software on your computing device, User Content you save will be stored locally on that device and synced with our servers. If you post or transfer any Information to or through our Site, Software, and/or Services, you are agreeing to such Information, including Personal Data and User Content, being hosted and accessed in the United States.

### How secure is my Information?

Internet data transmissions, whether wired or wireless, cannot be guaranteed to be 100% secure, and as a result, we cannot ensure the security of Information you transmit to us, including Personal Data and User Content; accordingly, you acknowledge that you do so at your own risk.

We use industry-standard encryption to protect your data in transit. This is commonly referred to as transport layer security (“TLS”) or secure socket layer (“SSL”) technology.

Once we receive your data, we protect it on our servers using a combination of technical, physical, and logical security safeguards. The security of the data stored locally in any of our Software installed on your computing device requires that you make use of the security features of your device. We recommend that you take the appropriate steps to secure all computing devices that you use in connection with our Site, Software, and Services.

If CIW learns of a security system breach, we may attempt to notify you and provide information on protective steps, if available, through the email address that you have provided to us or by posting a notice on the Site. Depending on where you live, you may have a legal right to receive such notices in writing.

### How you delete your Personal Data from CIW

You can remove your Personal Data from Grammarly at any time by contacting us [here](https://www.chinainternetwatch.com/contact/). Please note that, for security reasons, CIW paid subscription users will first be instructed to cancel their subscriptions before they can delete their CIW account.

### How long is Personal Data retained?

You can remove your Personal Data from CIW at any time by deleting your account as described above. However, we may keep some of your Personal Data for as long as reasonably necessary for our legitimate business interests, including fraud detection and prevention and to comply with our legal obligations.

### What happens if CIW closes my account?

If CIW closes your account due to your violation of the Terms of Service, then you may contact CIW to request deletion of your data. CIW will evaluate such requests on a case by case basis, pursuant to our legal obligations.

### Individuals located in the European Economic Area (EEA)

Individuals located in the European Economic Area (EEA) have certain rights in respect to their personal information, including the right to access, correct, or delete Personal Data we process through your use of the Site, Software, and/or Services. If you’re a user based in the EEA, you can:

  * Request a Personal Data report by submitting a Premium Support ticket through [this link](https://www.chinainternetwatch.com/account/). This report will include the Personal Data we have about you, provided to you in a structured, commonly used, and portable format. You must be signed into your CIW account to submit this request on Premium Support tab. Please note that CIW may request additional information from you to verify your identity before we disclose any information.

  * Have your Personal Data corrected or deleted. Some Personal Data can be updated by you: You can update your name and email address, as well as language preference, through your CIW account settings.

  * Object to us processing your Personal Data. You can ask us to stop using your Personal Data, including when we use your Personal Data to send you marketing emails. We only send marketing communications to users located in the EEA with your prior consent, and you may withdraw your consent at any time by clicking the “unsubscribe” link found within CIW emails and changing your contact preferences. Please note you will continue to receive transactional messages related to our Services, even if you unsubscribe from marketing emails.

  * Complain to a regulator. If you’re based in the EEA and think that we haven’t complied with data protection laws, you have a right to lodge a complaint with your local supervisory authority.

You may contact us with any questions relating to this Privacy Policy by submitting a request [here](https://www.chinainternetwatch.com/account/).
